To,
The Manager (HR)
Subject: - Application for to be associate with your esteemed organization
Respected Sir/Madam,
I take this opportunity to introduce myself as Commerce Graduate and passed CA Inter from the Institute of Chartered Accountants of India (ICAI), have Seven Years of relevant work experience.
I understand that your organization operates in a professional, dynamic and vibrant environment. I am absolutely sure that there would be extremely challenging and growth oriented career opportunities existing in your organization. All this positively motivates me to explore an appropriate opening with your organization.
I am enclosing my Curriculum Vitae herewith for your kind perusal. I am looking forward for an opportunity to meet you and exploring possibilities further.
Thanking You
Yours Truly,
(Rajnish Kumar)
Date:
Place:

CURRICULUM VITAE

Rajnish Kumar

A-5, Gali No.- 4 Rajapuri, Uttam Nagar New Delhi - 110059 (Willing to relocate)

Contact No.: +91-8860620595

Email id.: rajnishkumar08@gmail.com

Career Objective

To work in pragmatic way in an organization where I can contribute my learning & experience in the best interest of the organization and enhance my learning & experience to meet organizational goals and objective with full integrity and zest.

Work Experience

❖ Pristine Logistics & Infraprojects Ltd. processes the Pan − Indian License from the Indian Railways to operate container trains from anywhere in India to anywhere. Pristine operates 3 ICDs (Inland Container Depots) at Kanpur, Ludhiana, and Patna. (Pristine Group − Kanpur Logistics Park Pvt Ltd, Pristine Mega Logistics Park Pvt Ltd, Pristine Magadh Infrastructure Pvt Ltd, Pristine Hindustan Infraprojects Pvt Ltd, Techlog Support Services Pvt Ltd and Indomatrix Logistics Pvt Ltd.

Organization : Pristine Mega Logistics Park Private Limited

Location : Head Office (Delhi)
Period : August 2018 to Till Date

Designation : Senior Executive- Finance & Account

Major Customers : Reliance Industries Ltd., ACC Ltd., Maersk Line,

Hapag-Lloyd & CMA CGM etc.

Turnover : Above 500Cr.

Responsibility

- Prepares and monitors asset, liability and journal entries by compiling and analyzing account information
- ➤ Ensured accuracy of revenue and expenses accounts
- Conduct monthly and quarterly account reconciliations to ensure accurate reporting and ledger maintenance
- ➤ Review all inter-company transactions and generate invoices as necessary
- Prepares Data, Payment and Filling GST Returns
- ➤ Prepares GST Reconciliation (GSTR-3B, GSTR-1, GSTR-2A & GSTR-2B)
- Prepares Data, Payment and Filing TDS Return
- Prepares TDS Reconciliation
- Cooperates with internal and external auditors
- Manages and support junior accountants and provided them with accounting advice

Organization : JSRP & Associates (Chartered Accountant)
Location : Head Office (Delhi) and Branch Office (Bihar)

Period : April 2014 to July 2018

Designation : Paid Assistant

Organization : Prem Amar & Co. (Chartered Accountant)

Location : Head Office (Delhi)

Period : April 2011 to April 2014

Designation : Paid Assistant

Articleship

Organization : Prem Amar & Co. (Chartered Accountant)

Location : Head Office (Delhi)

Period : April 2008 to April 2011

Designation : Article/Audit Assistant

Organization : Lath S Kumar & Associates (Chartered Accountant)

Location : Head Office (Delhi)

Period : October 2007 to March 2008

Designation : Article Assistant

Business Profile of the Firm:

The core business of firm of Chartered Accountants is to provide services of Auditing & Accounting, Direct & Indirect Taxation consultancy and other ROC Compliance to Corporate Clients. More over services are also provided to a number of Societies, Trusts, Partnership firms, Sole Proprietorships etc.

Key Result Areas

Audits

- ➤ Tax Audit & Statutory Audit of various types of clients
- Vouching, Verification
- Reconciliation & Scrutiny of Ledgers
- ➤ Physical verification of Fixed Assets

Taxation

GST

- ➤ GST Registration and filing of online GST Returns.
- Preparing GST Return from Tally Software
- Reconcile GST Input and Output with GST Portal

INCOME TAX

- ➤ E-Filing of Income Tax Returns for various types of assesse
- ➤ Periodic TDS returns for corporate and non-corporate client
- ➤ Revise/Correction of TDS returns
- ➤ Handling of TDS & Income Tax Notices & scrutiny cases

Accounting

- ➤ Preparation and Finalisation of Financial Accounts while complying with all statutory obligations.
- ➤ Handling the Branch Accounting and intercompany Transactions and regularly reconciling ledger and scrutinize them.
- ➤ Compliance with the Accounting Standards

Educational Qualifications

Stage	University/ Board	Year of Passing
CA Inter	ICAI	2009
B. Com. (H)	BNMU	2017
Intermediate	BSEB	2007
Matriculation	BSEB	2005

Computer Proficiency

- Well versed with MS- Word & Excel like Pivot Table, VLOOKUP etc.
- Well versed with Accounting Software like Tally Prime, Busy and SAP (Level-Beginner)
- Well versed with Internet applications, TDS & GST Software etc.
- Completed Computer Training Program from ICAI

Personal Details

Father's name : Shri Deep Narayan Yadav

• DOB : July 16, 1990

Gender : MaleMarital Status : Married

• Languages known : English, Hindi

(Rajnish Kumar)